<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Thoughts on Vetle&#39;s Tech Chronicles</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Vetle&#39;s Tech Chronicles</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Why Your Naming Convention is Slowing You Down</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/naming-conventions/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/naming-conventions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep. I hate naming things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most, if not all companies, loves to create global naming conventions for their resources. These conventions often become counterproductive and make creating resources a chore. Also, when you&amp;rsquo;re working with multiple customers at once, this becomes an even greater challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hidden-costs-of-complex-names&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-hidden-costs-of-complex-names&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Hidden Costs of Complex Names
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive overhead&lt;/strong&gt;: A name like &lt;code&gt;app-p-nwe-rg&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t easy to read; it&amp;rsquo;s a code that needs deciphering. This adds mental friction for everyone who interacts with the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brittleness and lies&lt;/strong&gt;: Cloud resources are dynamic. What happens when the app in &lt;code&gt;nwe&lt;/code&gt; (Norway East) is migrated to West Europe? Renaming is often impossible, so the name becomes a lie, making it even harder to understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintenance and enforcement&lt;/strong&gt;: You have to write extensive documentation for the naming convention, build complex validation rules (e.g., regex in pipelines), and constantly update both. This is a time sink that doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Different world views&lt;/strong&gt;: People are different. Some will try to change it to support their specific view of the world. This adds friction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;names-for-humans-tags-for-machines&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#names-for-humans-tags-for-machines&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Names for Humans, Tags for Machines
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resource names should describe its &lt;strong&gt;purpose&lt;/strong&gt;, while its metadata should be handled by &lt;strong&gt;tags&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
