<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Terraform on Vetle&#39;s Tech Chronicles</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/terraform/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Terraform on Vetle&#39;s Tech Chronicles</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Manage Multiple Terraform Environments</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/multi-environment-terraform/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/multi-environment-terraform/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every project starts simple, but when managing infrastructure for &lt;code&gt;dev&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;test&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;prod&lt;/code&gt;, let alone multiple customers, it quickly becomes complex. How can we solve this chaos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll tackle the common issues of scalable IaC, and go through a clear journey from basic patterns to something more advanced, showing you how to choose the right tool for the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isolated-folders&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#isolated-folders&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Isolated Folders
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the classic starting point when trying to figure out multi-environment setups. Its the simplest way to manage multiple environments by giving each one its own dedicated directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Solve Terraform Drift</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/solve-terraform-drift/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/solve-terraform-drift/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-terraform-drift&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-terraform-drift&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is Terraform Drift?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Drift is the term for when the real-world state of your infrastructure differs from the state defined in your configuration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;― &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Christie Koehler, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hashicorp.com/en/blog/detecting-and-managing-drift-with-terraform&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;HashiCorp Blog&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be caused by many things, but urgent hotfixes and teams being unfamiliar with Infrastructure as Code (IaC) practices is the most likely cause. Its a significant problem because it undermines the core benefits of IaC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main issue is the loss of a single source of truth. When your code and infra tell different stories, you can no longer trust your code to be an accurate representation of your environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Develop Terraform Modules</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/develop-terraform-modules/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/develop-terraform-modules/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monorepo-vs-multi-repo&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#monorepo-vs-multi-repo&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Monorepo vs Multi-repo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Terraform Monorepo&lt;/strong&gt; (or &lt;strong&gt;Terralith&lt;/strong&gt;), keeps all of your Terraform modules in a single Git repository, often in a &lt;code&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt; directory. While simple at first, this pattern makes it difficult for other teams to reuse your modules and complicates versioning. It&amp;rsquo;s generally considered an anti-pattern unless the modules are highly specific to a single application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you should almost always use the &lt;strong&gt;multi-repo&lt;/strong&gt; pattern. Each module lives in its own dedicated Git repository. This approach makes your module a standalone component that is easy to share, maintain, and version. Consumers of your module can then reference a specific version using a Git tag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Eliminate Secrets From Your Terraform Azure Backend</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/azure-terraform-github-actions-oidc/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/azure-terraform-github-actions-oidc/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-oidc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-oidc&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is OIDC?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OIDC&lt;/strong&gt; stands for &lt;strong&gt;OpenID Connect&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an identity layer built on top of the OAuth 2.0 framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms, it allows one application (like a GitHub Actions workflow) to securely prove its identity to another application (like a cloud provider such as Azure) without using static, long-lived secrets. Instead, the system uses a short-lived, verifiable ID Token. This process of exchanging a temporary token is often called a &amp;ldquo;federated identity&amp;rdquo; workflow and is a much more secure way to manage authentication for automated processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Build a Hugo Website on Azure</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/hugo-site-azure/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/hugo-site-azure/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#prerequisites&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Prerequisites
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before you begin, ensure you have the following set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;Azure&lt;/strong&gt; account with an active subscription. Make sure it has the Entra ID role &lt;code&gt;Application Administrator&lt;/code&gt;, and Azure &lt;code&gt;Owner&lt;/code&gt; role on the subscription.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locally installed tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Git, Azure CLI, and a code editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Optional)&lt;/strong&gt; A custom domain name purchased from any registrar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;repository-setup&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#repository-setup&#34; class=&#34;header-anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Repository Setup
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To streamline the process, a GitHub template is provided. This template contains all the necessary Terraform, GitHub Actions, and Hugo boilerplate files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
